hey everybody welcome to this a one
English listening practice video you can
use this video to practice your
listening and comprehension as I speak
before we start remember to subscribe to
the channel click on the bell and follow
us on Instagram you ready so today I'm
gonna talk about soccer this is a really
popular topic because many people love
soccer soccer is the most popular sport
in the world it's the most important
sport in the world let's talk first
about the rules of soccer
the objective of the game is to score
more goals than the other team if your
team scores more goals than the other
team your team wins and the other team
loses but it's not easy to score goals
it's hard each team has defenders who
try to stop you from scoring goals
midfielders are the players that play in
the middle of the field they have to run
a lot
I never liked being a midfielder because
I can't run a lot the players that
usually score goals are called forwards
being a forward is fun because scoring
goals is fun also each team has a
goalkeeper the goalkeeper can use his
hands and his whole body to defend the
goal in total each team has 11 players
on the field now let's talk about
soccers popularity in most countries
soccer is the biggest sport most cities
have a local soccer team and the people
support their city's team there are also
national teams every four years national
teams compete for the World Cup during
this time everyone supports their kind
trees team some nations are very good
like Germany France and Brazil other
nations are not so good the US doesn't
have a very good team because soccer is
not very popular in the u.s. most
Americans prefer other sports like
American football basketball and
baseball
many children play soccer in the US but
not many people enjoy watching soccer I
played soccer when I was a child and it
was fun for me I liked being a forward
because I wanted to score goals I don't
play soccer now though ok lastly let's
talk about soccer leagues around the
world most countries have a domestic
soccer league with local teams some
famous soccer leagues include the
English Premier League La Liga and Spain
Bundesliga in Germany and sedia ah and
Italy these leagues have some very good
teams some of the best teams in the
world include rau Madrid Barcelona
Liverpool Bayern Munich and Juventus in
the past I really liked watching
Cristiano Ronaldo
play I watched him play for rounded rid
Juventus and Portugal my favourite
matches are the Champions League matches
the Champions League is the highest
competition for European teams every
year in the Champions League the best
teams in the world play against each
other it's always really exciting
nowadays I'm not really interested in
sports anymore but once in a while
I like watching soccer alright that's
all for today leave a comment and tell
me
who your favorite soccer team is and
remember to subscribe to the channel
click on the bell and follow us on
Instagram for more English tips and
lessons I'll see you next time
[Music]
[Applause]